### Gondi Bhanuprakash Reddy (1) Featured



Full Stack Developer seeking assignment in Full Stack Development, Software

Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project

Management, Requirement

Gathering, SDLC, Html, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Ajax, Nodejs, Angular JS, Apache

Spark, Scala, Kafka



Current Designation: Full Stack Developer Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Technologies Pvt.Ltd. Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: BTECH [electrical]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Pune, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Full Stack Developer, Software Developer, Full Stack Development, Software Development, Application

Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement

Gathering, SDLC, Html, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Ajax, Nodejs, Angular JS, Apache Spark, Scala

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 20-Jan-21 Last Active: 20-Jan-21

## Summary

More than 9+ years of extensive experience in Software Development Life Cycle, developing Web, Enterprise and Product applications with N-tier architecture with Core Java, J2EE or open source web technology.

Excellent knowledge of all the phases of software development life cycle (Requirements gathering, analysis, design, development, testing and implementation).

Good experience on working with Amazon Web Services like EC2, S3, Amazon Simple DB, Amazon RDS, Amazon Elastic Load Balancing, Amazon SQS, AWS Identity and access management, AWS Cloud Watch, Amazon EBS and Amazon Cloud Front

Good Experience of Web Services (SOAP, WSDL, AXIS2, JAX-RPC, JAXB2.0, JAX-WS2.0, Rest).

Good Experience in Hibernate, Spring boot and Spring (IOC,AOP,ORM & MVC)Frameworks.

Good Experience of UI Development (Html, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Ajax, Nodejs and Angular JS 1 (Angular 2, 5,6,7)), react js.

# **Work Experience**

Capgemini Technologies Pvt.Ltd. as Full Stack Developer

Jun 2017 to Till Date

Project#1(Senior Consultant): Project: Trade Service(HIE, HFE4),

Client: HSBC Software Development Pvt Ltd.,

Technologies: Core java 8, Web Services (Soap/Rest),

JavaScript, Anugularis, Webspare Application Server, JIRA, Confluence, IBM MQ, RAD, Spring Boot, G3, WINSP, G3/PCF(Deployment Tool), aws,

Nexus Repository, Agile, WSBCC, kafka and spark.

**Environment: Windows XP** 

Team Size: 15

Duration: June 2017 to Still

#### Contribution:

HIE(Hub Import and Export) services using HFE4/4c Application.

Different Region to Deployment for Live using G3 Tool,

Testing for UAT and SIT.

Used Amazon Cloud Watch to monitor AWS services and Amazon Cloud Watch logs to monitor application.

Amazon EC2 is also used for deploying and testing the lower environments such as Dev and Test.

Object storage service Amazon S3 is used to store and retrieve media files

Developed AngularJS Single Page Application consuming JSON data from Restful services.

Kafka integration with Spark using Spark Streaming API.

Worked on Scala for implementing spark machine learning libraries and spark streaming.

Sent messages to Strom using Kafka messaging tool

Using UI technologies Front side development.

### IBM India Pvt Ltd., (Magna Infotech) as Tech Lead

Feb 2016 to Apr 2016

Project: Legal Portal.

Client: Vodafone India Pvt Ltd.,

Technologies: Core java 8, Web Services (Soap/Rest), Angular Js, Node Js,

JavaScript, Jquery.

**Environment: Windows XP** 

Team Size: 5 Contribution:

Developed front-end code with Ajax call in AngularJS and jQuery to retrieve data as JSON Object from controllers in backend RESTful Server, then display the well organized result in web pages by writing AngularJS controller, directives, services, and route providers. Also used Angular.js filter to make the data searchable.

Configured the web.xml file for REST server injection to enable the REST web services by using JAXB API.

Responsible for designing the User Interface by coding in HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, Bootstrap to build this SPA Single Page Application .

Created the Node.js EXPRESS Server combined with Socket.io to build MVC framework from front-end side AngularJS to back-end MongoDB.

Description:

Legal Security CDR Application is developed to make Vodafone comply with the TRAI/DoT requirements for security related guidelines. The DoT requirement entails maintaining 12 months CDR data which will be available online through an application. The application aims to provide CDR data to Government Agency like CBI, ATS, and State Police etc. to investigate legal matters. Vodafone Nodal Officer uses this application over the Vodafone Intranet to access the CDR data on request of these Govt Agency.

### Infosys Limited (BR Ray Soft) as Technical Lead

Jul 2015 to Oct 2015

Project : centurion card Client: Amex(American Express)

Technologies: core java, XML, JavaScript, Html, Jquery, Rally Tool,

Maven Tool, Nodejs, Angular js.

Environment: windows xp

Testing : Selenium and Cucumber

Team Size

Duration : July 2015 - October 2015

Contribution:

Working in Scaled Agile Framework environment

TDD/BDD approach with Selenium & Cucumber

Maintaining visibility of sprint/release content & metrics using Rally

Facilitating stand ups, retrospectives, sprint reviews, sprint planning, grooming

Removing blockers and helping teams to remove blockers themselves

Used JavaScript, for the client end data validations.

Used XML for the sever side validation

Application Implemented as a single-page, Angular.js Client.

Creating e2e test suites for all components, and running them with Protractor (or a well reasoned alternative) with Node

Key technologies: HTML, JAVA, Java Script, Angular Js, Node Js, JQuery, XML, Maven, Jenkins, iCM, etc.

Description:

A banking project which is a middleware application which involves risk check and validation of customer information of an online application which can be used by the customers of the bank and the bank to allow a tax payer or a tax firm to enrol into application and do all the servicing and storing the details.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2007

PG: BTECH (electrical) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2007

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SOAP,WSDL,AXIS2,JAX-RPC			
JAXB2.0,JAX-WS2.0, Rest			
Hibernate, Spring Boot			
Spring (IOC,AOP,ORM & MVC)Frameworks			
Html, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Ajax			
Nodejs and Angular JS 1			
Spring Boot, Spring Micro Services			
Spring (IOC,AOP,MVC),			
Apache spark,scala,kafka			
Selenium, Cucumber,Junit, karma, Jasmin			

# **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time